Guide to the John Taylor, Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
11 AL to various recipients; Salop
1726-1728
OSBORN C357
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.04
(1 volume)
Letters to various friends from his years at Cambridge University.
Taylor, John, 1704-1766
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn c357. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Letters; Great Britain -- Intellectual life -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Shropshire (England); Drake, James, fl. 1734; Pegge, Samuel, 1733-1800; Taylor, John, 1704-1766; St. John's College (University of Cambridge)
- Osborn c357
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to Robert Cholmeley (b.1703), 1727 Jan 5 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Salop
      4 p.; 19 x 15 cm.
      Literary topics and personalities,
      including remarks about Edmund
      Curll, a printer (1675-1747) and
      William Pattison (1706-1727).
      357/2
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to Robert Cholmeley (b.1703), 1726 Sep 3 (Box 1)
      4 p.; 21 x 16
      Pokes fun at Cholmeley's prospective
      stay in London.
      357/11
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to James Drake (b. 1703), 1728 Sep 17 (Box 1)
      Cambridge
      2 p.; 22 x 17 cm.
      Humorous letter to a friend after an
      "intermission of our epistolary
      correspondence."
      357/1
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to John Holcombe (b. 1704), 1727 Oct 30 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      Literary subjects; belittles his own
      creative accomplishments and recalls
      his former complaints about the "sad
      dearth of wit...in these uncouth
      regions"; he corrects himself and
      writes about the "remarkable" manners
      and polish of the area.
      357/7
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to John Holcombe (b. 1704), n.d. (Box 1)
      Chides his friend for not answering
      his letters; admits he misses
      Cambridge and his college friends
      tells of his dislike of Salop and the
      disagreeable nature of his neighbors.
      357/9
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to Samuel Pegge (1704-1796), 1727 Dec 6 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 20 x 15 cm.
      Friendly letter concerns antiquarian
      topics and regrets about a lost note.
      357/4
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to William Rothery (b. 1705), 1727 Feb 10 (Box 1)
      Chides friend for not returning his
      letter; comments on literary topics
      and criticizes Edmund Curll
      (1675-1747), a printer, and William
      Pattison (1706-1727).
      357/5
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to Edward Rynaston, 1726 Jul 30 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      Thanks Rynaston for his letter and
      inquires as to why William Rothery
      (b.1705) has not written.
      357/10
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to William Salisbury (1706-1796), 1727 Jan 20 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      Discusses his passion for Greek,
      poetry, and women.
      357/6
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to William Salisbury (1706-1796), 1727 Dec 6 (Box 1)
      357/8
  - TAYLOR, JOHN, 1704-1766
    - AL (draft) to himself, 1727 Dec 4 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 21 x 16
      Discusses the challenges of
      corresponding with himself and
      begins: "I am heartily sorry for yr
      very great mischief you have brought
      upon yr self in desiring to establish
      a correspondence wth me - Why, I am
      afraid you don't know me...."
      357/3